I created this piece in 2017 out of wanting a desired
of protest these neonauts that we heard that were coming to
Pockville, Kentucky, which is about an hour from Wantsburg.
And it actually came out of, because I was working with the
Appalachian Media Institute at the time, as an assistant
basically, and working with the youth there, and we'd started
like a youth drop-in stinner.
And one of the kids, when we were talking about this happening,
he suggested an art and response day, which I thought was an
incredible suggestion from like a 16-year-old kid.
And so we all decided that was a great way to think about it
and to art as always a great therapeutic source, I think.
And so we had the art and response day, the not before.
I get a lot of my ideas when I'm like, and I think it's
general and general, like a lot of artists do, but when you're
wanting to solve some problem in your head, but then you're
doing something else that's not, you can turn off that part
of your brain is logical and stuff.
And so I was cooking in the kitchen or something, and I
actually remember rotten were in my house.
It came, you know, the thought came to me, but it just
this phrase, no, I ain't in my hall or popped into my head.
And I knew, I just knew immediately that that was going to be
the piece I made the next day.
And so I do a lot of printmaking, and printmaking has had a
long history of being accessible, especially for protests.
And you know, it's a great and easy way for people to
replicate posters, to print on t-shirts, and stuff like that.
So I thought that that would be the best way for me to make
the piece the next day.
And I didn't really think much about the design other than
I wanted it to look like the region here, you know, and
he's starting to take in Appalachia.
And it all just came together, and I did this block that was,
you know, I don't know, live in my 14 or something.
And at the bottom, I put the hashtag Go Home Nazi Scum
because that was really what we were fighting against these
neo-nautsies that had shared posters about the plot of the
plot family and how that we, you know, the plot family really
had to be careful, and we needed to lift each other up and
all this stuff.
So it was like, I think they were trying to fool people about,
you know, it wasn't lightenly racist, but it was,
they're lightenly racist if that makes sense.
Like you didn't have to read too far into it to see that they
were lots of premises.
And so from there, I made the piece.
A bunch of us might artwork that day.
It was a really great day.
And I posted it on my social media page, and it kind of took off.
And people in the area were just like, I want this on a
t-shirt, and with this on a poster, I want to, you know, have this
for the day that these people come to our region and try to force
their beliefs on us, and also like, we don't want them here.
You know, so there was a really great response to the, to the
piece I made, and to just in general, people not wanting to have
any part of what they were trying to say.
So I started, I do screen printing too.
I did a few like block printed t-shirts, but I do screen printing too.
And then from there, it just kind of grew and it has been,
it's really kind of awful because every time there's something
terrible that has happened, people want this piece, you know,
to, to, to fat against it.
So, you know, early on, while we were still trying to protest the,
neo-Nalcus that were coming the pack roll, I was like, you know, this
could, I think I could do some good with this.
And so I decided to always donate at least 25% of the profits that
I might from this piece towards some sort of,
organization, nonprofit organization, an Eastern Kentucky or
Central Apple Latch that is fouting for our quality and equity in
some way.
So, to date, I've been able to raise over $9,000.
And I do all the work across sale for command shirts.
When, bring on a Tyler and George Floyd around that time when
they were murdered, I think I printed like 500 t-shirts or
something.
So I raised, yeah, I mean, it was, it was pretty incredible.
I mean, I, you know, I got to raise for a Black Lives Matter.
And I've donated to several different organizations, like I said.
And so it also kind of grew into a, I love ship for LGBTQ communities.
And so it's, it's grown in ways that I didn't imagine it would.
And I have received so many comments from people like just
the other day.
Well, I'm acquaintances with them, but they messaged me.
And he said, you know, I finally got to change my name to Lee.
And he gave your permission to tell the story.
But he sent me a picture with his certificate of name change.
And, you know, that he had, he had just no hide my haul shirt on.
So that just was really meaningful.
Sorry.
But it's just, it's been pretty incredible.
Just what a piece of art can do just in general.
So I played around with, you know, with different color schemes for it.
And then I did get a couple requests.
Because I was doing a, you know, prints, mostly for it.
And I did get a request for, you know, different color, like the rainbow color scheme and stuff.
And I was like, you know, if people want this and they identify with it,
then I want to provide that for them.
And it really has kind of, it's got a lot of its own like it's grown beyond me.
And, you know, that's, I think what most artists like during creating a piece
that could do that in some way, you know, I think artists reflect the time period that they're in.
You know, and so I think that it has, it has been a source of, well, you know,
that there was an article written about it shortly after that protest in, in, in Pogville,
which my dad that the only people that showed up to it were people who were trying to protest,
you know, the neo-Nazis, they didn't want it to make you hear.
And so it, and it, I think they just left them eventually.
So it was peaceful, which is what we all wanted.
And a journalist contacted me and did a story about it.
So he did a story and was called like no height, no height, my collar, an apple-action war cry.
And I just thought that that was like such a great, just such a great phrase to go with it.
I just thought, you know, it was just, I hadn't thought of it in that way.
So yeah, it's just been really incredible to see the growth and to see how important it is to people
and how it has grown beyond me.
And so there was a couple of several communities that put no height, my collar up on billboards.
And there was a, after one of them came down, there was a billboard that went up, that said something like,
only Jesus and my holler or something.
And I was like, how are those two things mutually exclusive?
Like I didn't understand how, it was, I mean, that just didn't make sense to me.
And so, so I, from that, I got the idea to do a heat and wrap up.
Because I was just like, you know, as a visual artist, it would be very cool to see where all this has gone.
And how it's kind of grown and who has adopted this phrase to, you know, and show them that there's no height in their holler.
So I asked my aunt and association, they used to be my seed, but I asked them if they would be interested in helping me find a graphic designer.
And put this together and they said, yes.
And so I was working with a lot agency in Irvine, which I think is where that billboard was initially put up.
And so just worked with me.
And so we did a heat map of every year since 2017, the growth of this message and where I've seen it, all this merchandise.
And it was just, it's kind of overwhelming to see, you know, it started out very centralized and Eastern Kentucky and a little bit into the scene Virginia.
And then from there, I just spread and spread and spread.
So I'm friends with Sylvia Rarson, you know, I've known her several years she worked at Apple shop and we kept in contact, you know, through the years since she lived.
And so she had actually contacted me.
And so I knew that this, that they were wanting to build this prison and I, you know, there's been several rounds of, I guess, protests about it.
And so I hadn't heard that they were still wanting to go through with it until she contacted me.
And first she was, you know, talking about just the meetings and that they were holding.
And then she asked me to design a t-shirt for them.
So, first concerned electric audience was the group.
And so I was like, that would be, you know, that aligns with me, you know, pretty well.
And so I was really excited.
So she shared the, like, EPA's, like, what's it called, you know, when they go in and say it's like, what animals and plants will be harmed.
And, you know, in the building.
And I don't know, she shared a lot of information with me.
And so we talked about what it should look like.
And then so she invited me to the Pizza Hut prisons.
And that's where I met you.
I, you know, I wanted to go to learn more about it and to talk to people that were there and to get an idea of what, what more the t-shirt could be about.
And also just to hear, I mean, I feel like a lot of the time this stuff is, like, kept, I mean, people put it out there, but it's, it's not, you know, there were people that didn't know that it was still even being talked about.
And so I think, if the, if the circle you want to know that it's happening sometimes, especially in these small communities.
And so I went on the way to the, to the event actually, you know, after the flood, because we had a record store in my studio, down the street, and then after the flood, we had to move up here to where I'm now.
And I was walking that building in the landlord popped in.
We were talking and she was like, are you going to that thing?
And she was like, what the, what the, she was like, that thing about the prison, they're at Apple shop. And I was like, yeah.
And she was like, why, why are you, why are you opposed? And so we kind of talked about it for a bit.
And it just, you know, there's so many people that can't see, we all in the possibility of jobs, or they don't want to, I'm not sure what it is.
I mean, we are like financially depressed here, but you know, all, all of the studies say that that is not going to save us, you know, that's not going to be a thing that will actually help.
And so anyway, yes, I was there to learn more and to, because I was opposed to having since the beginning, but it was something that I had not been able to actually attend anything prior.
And because I didn't, I didn't hear a whole lot about it. You know, Sylvia is not in the community anymore.
And I know some of the people that were there too that still are, but like I said, it's sometimes things are not necessarily kept secret on purpose. But if you're not in the right circles, and you don't always know what's happening.
I think there would have been a whole lot more there. There was a man there that lived on property near the prison, or what it would be, and what's very upset because he couldn't go hunting.
And I mean, I think there's people that would identify with that. And if they knew more about it, and it's like, how do we get those people to listen and to understand and to learn about what will actually happen if the prison is here.
Yeah. And even like the construction of the slogans, right? Like you're both saying no, no, let your prison, no hate in my hauler.
For me, of course, like that being the first time I've seen you in person, of course, that's what I thought of. And that being me, I'm like, no, hey, no prison. Okay, here we go.
I don't know if those like are connected for you at all, or if you know, I think, you know, I think there is such a history of racism in the prison complex that I do think.
I mean, well, yeah, as soon as like, so if you asked me to do it to your shirt and ask me to kind of this, I was like, yeah, that allows with what I believe because no hate in my hauler that covers a plethora of hate, you know what I think.
You know, the prison complex is very greedy. There is a racist contingent to that. And yeah, it really, I think no, hate in my hauler of fiat into that so well.
You know, I don't know. I think you're exactly right. And I was, I was thinking about it. And I, you know, I do want to do as an artist, like I said, you know, they, they fit the time period that they're in and they make work about that.
I mean, you know, making the t-shirt for that. I mean, you know, what better way to protest and help that movement than to create work that's that's about no prisons here.
So, you know, I'm definitely, no hate in my hauler is definitely a no it's your prisons.
And so no hate in my hauler fits all haulers, you know, it's, it's a, and why do we need that here? Like why do we need, I mean, it's, I feel like it's a how Rogers like ego booster, you know, I mean, we don't need a prison here. We need other things like that is not going to benefit the land, the people.
It's just, it's, it's, it's kind of mortifying to think about it that that's something that is being considered for this county.
Yeah. And we don't need it here and we don't need another home anywhere. Yeah. Yeah. We don't need energy.
Yeah. Yeah. Like think about like look through all these prisoners who are in jail for like selling weed. Like I mean, we don't need, you know, we don't need more prisons. We need to rethink the
synopsis of people that I mean, you know, it's just, it's such a mess. It's so again about greed, I think.
And racism, you know, I think those two things are two of the posts that are holding the prison complex.
You're giving us such like structural analysis, like their structural racism and anti capitalism coming out of no hate in my hauler.
Living for it.
Yeah. I grew up poor. I grew up, you know, in a hauler, I grew up with kids of different, you know, colors on backgrounds. And like I said, you know, I, I was raised as a person of, you know, a belief that, you know, you care for your neighbor and try to help them.
You don't punish them just because they're different. And that's, you know, so much of my work comes from that place of, you know, I try to lead with love. That's how I try to lead my life. I don't always succeed. I'm sure that I try really hard. And, you know, prisons have nothing to do with loving your neighbor or loving anyone.
And no hate in my mother, you know, there's been, you know, whenever the first billboard went up, the reporter was like, do not, because they did a story of the local TV station.
And they're like, do not read the comments. And I was like, okay. And then he messaged me. He's like, actually, the comments aren't bad. But I don't know how long they weren't bad. But I was just like, how can anyone argue this message?
Like it does like, are you for hate? Like, what could you say about it that would make you feel good? Again, I'm off on a tangent. But yeah.
No, I think you're spot on. I think you're spot on. Like the prison generates hate. It generates racism. It generates divisiveness. Right. And so, like, I feel like no hate in my hall or speaks directly to that.
And then it has a legacy from 2017 to 2024 to the future. You have this heat map where we're going to continue documenting how masses speak and slogans and like this slogan has grown and will continue to grow in different communities.
And I think that's why I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like
it's like it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like, I think it's like I think it's like , I think it's like, I think it's like try and I think it's like automated university.
But then it's like I think it's like it's like, I even used a plastic fund and I never used a plastic like a plastic fund, but it was like!, I think, it was a big system.
I think that this thing is likeballs and Editor of America and it's like, it was like, geen giveaway, a small machine like Pokemon.
And I think it's like, plus that you could, but I think, myが, we could function to get things done.
much damage, but I know what that is like in people's lives and I think really trying to figure out a way
and I think art is one of the main ways we do that in conversations like with your neighbor. It's
like how do we how do we collectively move towards something that's also you know yes this is the
thing you want in your hauler and you know that looks like this and it will bring you know because I
can hear people's grief my kids are gone everything's gone we're devastated we're all these things
um but turning that into a demand instead of you know taking a prison for cheap
on this you know not but anyway I love everything you say that was just a comment but
yeah and I think again just to the possibility of what art can do is like
folks at that hearing really really do cling or did cling to the idea of the prison as the
singular solution and artists that we are speaking to and preserving their work are
articulating otherwise in their pieces and their artwork and saying actually there are alternatives
and like we that's that's what we want to do like artists also a conversation and
really appreciate you sharing I am from Kingsport Tennessee so I'm nearby
and we drove through Kingsport on the way to Letcher County and I was feeling very emotional as well
and seeing you was just like really powerful so yeah art I think is so it can be so powerful
and I've seen it in so many different you know this project and I'm doing community murals and
I just think it can really bring bring people together and and I appreciate when people reach out to
me and ask questions like you did um I try to answer as honestly and genuinely as I can because I
um I'm trying to move out of you know I've been reading a lot about art lately in Ego and it's
um I'm trying to release that part that might make me feel competitive and think of it more as
like a spiritual like movement and you know and um and I really do try to help you know artists
that are up and coming or just people that have questions or you know it's it's um I just think
it's so important to share knowledge and your experience and um so yeah I just appreciate
you reaching out initially and it was great to actually meet you in person and um yeah in Ego
excuse me you're a lot spurg I'll review like come to my studio and say ha